Diheng Zhang

76 Foster Rd. • Belmont, MA 02478 • (917)-861-0223 • dz2241@tc.columbia.edu

Summary

Research assistant, with 3 years of experience and skills that include:

Research: Institutional Review Board(IRB) application, Poster, Paper & Grant writing, EEG, Eye tracker **Software:** MS Word/Execl/PowerPoint, SPSS, M-Plus, Atlas.TI, E-Prime, Qualtrics, Surveymonkey

OS & Programming Languages: MS Windows, Unix & Mac OS; C/C++, Html, LATEX, Python, Matlab & R Studio

Language: Proficient in Cantonese and Mandarin

Related Experience

• Columbia University, Teachers College

Research Assistant for Department of Clinical Psychology

New York, NY Apr. 2013 – Present

- Initiated partnership with researchers in Jiang Xi, China to collaborate on adolescent developmental study

• Bellevue Hospital Center & New York University, Langone Medical Center Research Assistant

New York, NY Sept. 2013 – May 2014

- Assessed concussion and other trauma patients to recruit eligible participants for research

- Ran experiment protocol including operating Eye Tracker to collect research data
- Kan experiment protocol including operating Eye Tracker to conect research data
- Followed up with participants to arrange further research appointments and evaluation
- Managed patient data for accurate documentation

• Hamilton Madison House

New York, NY

Intern

Sept. 2013 – May 2014

- Completed case management responsibilities to facilitate in organization daily operations
- Helped with annual assessment to update case files
- Designed and co-led supporting and training groups to assist recovery of Schizophrenia patients

• Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center

Boston, MA

Research Assistant, Summer Intern

Jun. 2013 - Aug. 2013

- Prepared interview tools, salivation and blood collecting kits to gather participants' information
- Tested and installed EEG and biofeedback equipment to set up experiment environment and collect data
- Searched and summarized research articles to support grant application

Harvard University

Cambridge, MA

Research Assistant for Department of Psychology, Summer Intern

May 2013 – August 2013

- Operated portable EEG, applied WAIS and delivered Iowa Gambling Test to collect experimental data
- Established dataset, calculated outcome and helped generate preliminary conclusion in Excel and Python
- Performed literature reviews on research articles applying fMRI on Default Mode Network to self-educate

Columbia University

New York, NY

Research Assistant for Mailman School of Public Health

Oct 2012 – May 2014

- Translated research interviews with Chinese immigrants with psychosis to prepare for further analysis
- Coded and trained lab members to code interview materials with Atlas.TI to extend original stigma model
- Prepared and submitted poster and symposium proposals to APA, AAPA to share research outcome

Education

• Columbia University

Teachers College, M.A. in Clinical Psychology, Concentrated in Research Methods, GPA: 3.84/4.00

New York, NY

Nanjing University

Nanjing, China

School of Social and Behavioral Science, B.S. in Psychology, GPA: 3.80/4.00

July 2012

May 2014